Gavin Stark

gavin@gstark.com 727-560-3116 Saint Petersburg, FL, 33703 https://www.linkedin.com/in/gastark https://github.com/gstark

Software engineer with broad experience in Back End Web, Front End Web, DevOps, and Operating Systems who creates, maintains, audits, and improves systems to fulfill clients' requirements. Proficient in determining requirements, coordinating developer teams, and creating and deploying applications.

Technical Proficiencies

Ruby (16 years)	Ruby on Rails (16 years)	Java (16 years)	C# (3 years)
TDD _(14 years)	Docker (5 years)	Linux (15 years)	C (34 years)
C++ (29 years)	JavaScript (16 years)	TypeScript (3 years)	HTML (16 years)
CSS (16 years)	React (4 years)	Heroku _(6 years)	Nginx (11 years)
VMWare (9 years)	MySQL (15 years)	PostgreSQL (6 years)	Windows (8 years)
Mentorship (12 years)	Management (16 years)		

Career Experience

Principal Software Engineer (Contractor), STRATACACHE (Real Digital Media division), Saint Petersburg, Florida

Jun 2022 - Current

- Continuing previous role in a contractor capacity.
- Lowered installation costs of in-store media playing devices by implementing a wifi and mobile based device configuration system in React
- Achieved first-to-market for ARM based tablet and shelf-edge display devices by porting existing Intel based operating system.
- Lowered AWS costs through analyzing and right-sizing EC2 and RDS instances.

Principal Engineer, Kin Insurance, Saint Petersburg, Florida

Jan 2022 - June 2022

- Contributed to an Event Source architecture for an accounting and billing system
- Mentored developers at all levels (associate through staff)
- Reviewed architecture proposals as part of the Architecture Review Board
- Performed code reviews for pull-requests across the organization
- Developed libraries and patterns for building internal APIs
- Contributed to the organizations Tech Vision on behalf of the CTO and VP of Architecture

Principal Engineer, STRATACACHE (Real Digital Media division), Saint Petersburg, Florida

2017 - Dec 2021

- Developed, maintained, and improved a large-scale Ruby on Rails project for over 15 years. Migrated from Rails version 0.9 through Rails version 6.1
- Built a Ruby back-end API that processes millions of requests and background jobs per day.

- Migrated a Ruby on Rails system to a JSON-API-based back-end, improving the marketability of the NEOCAST digital signage management system.
- Built automated test code in Ruby and Cucumber to automate the testing of embedded hardware.
- Used RSpec to provide full test coverage of the authorization layer in the Rails JSON-API
- Developed a React front-end application to leverage a JSON-API back-end for customers to manage their digital signage networks
- Enabled new markets by creating and maintaining a custom Ubuntu-based OS that supported 32-bit Intel, 64-bit Intel, and ARM-64 based embedded systems.
- Achieved first-to-market amongst other divisions in a transition to the ARM platform by developing and implementing custom kernel patches for ARM-64 systems.
- Lowered hardware platform costs by maintaining a single application architecture for 32-bit Intel, 64-bit Intel, ARM-64, and Android devices.
- Built Ruby based AWS automation software to deploy and scale a docker-based infrastructure. This led to a reduction in hosting costs.

Senior Instructor, Suncoast Developers Guild, Saint Petersburg, Florida

2018 - Dec 2021

- Designed and implemented an interactive and engaging curriculum for multiple courses.
- Contributed to internal app generator: <u>app-app</u>. Based on react-scripts, builds student starter projects.
- Contributed to a 95% placement rate by identifying, recommending, and guiding students to secure positions as junior developers.
- Expanded market from full-time in-person classes into remote, part-time courses by developing an open-source curriculum for Ruby, C#, Entity Framework, ASP.NET, HTML, CSS, Responsive Web, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Deployment, and Algorithmic Thinking.
- Reduced overhead by developing a Rails-based student management system to effectively handle multiple operations, including enrollment, homework assignment, grading, and student progress reports.

Instructor and Product Development, The Iron Yard, Saint Petersburg, Florida

2015 - 2017

- Increased enrollment at one of the most profitable campuses at the largest in-person code school through developing and implementing a curriculum for Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node, Express, Algorithmic Thinking, and Deployment.
- Built a learning management application in Ruby on Rails to manage student information, assignments, and performance.

Principal Software Engineer, Real Digital Media, Saint Petersburg, Florida

2005 - 2015

- Designed, architected, and implemented a Ruby on Rails based software-as-a-service digital signage platform recognized as the most adaptable and easy to use in the market.
- Managed a team developing Ruby on Rails applications to provide a remote management web application to operate our customer's digital signage networks.
- Maintained excellent application availability by building infrastructure that processes millions of requests background jobs per day.
- Increased application uptime and fault tolerance by building and deploying an AWS infrastructure and software deployment strategy, including multi-zone redundancy.
- Continually lowered operational costs by migrating infrastructure from one server in a closet through a data center transition to a scalable Amazon Web Services based architecture over the course of the application's lifetime.
- Improved customer support by creating Ruby API for customer service dashboards and alerts.
- Ensured continuity of business functions by building disaster recovery policies and code, including offsite

- content and database backups.
- Opened new hardware markets by developing Linux and Android software and custom Linux distributions to run on embedded and PC platforms.
- Increased platform reliability and uptime of thousands of remote devices by creating a custom Ubuntu-based operating system designed to boot from a single squashfs root filesystem combined with an overlay filesystem allowing for secure and reliable remote upgrades.
- Increased the number of hardware platforms supported by patching Linux hardware drivers for device incompatibilities and missing features.
- Reduced the complexity of supporting a diverse array of platforms spanning over 30 hardware configurations, from custom system-on-chip to off-the-shelf hardware, including migrations from 32 to 64-bit operating systems and software.
- Built online Ruby on Rails report generator producing CSV, XML, JSON, and PDF reports.
- Expanded markets to new customers by designing and building an interactive editor for creating digital signage presentations containing multi-zone and multi-screen configurations.

Community Leadership

BarCamp Tampa Bay - 2007 to 2017 - Founding member of BarCamp Tampa Bay

Ignite Tampa Bay - 2011 to 2017 - Founding member of Ignite Tampa Bay

Coder Night - 2017 to 2021 - Organized a meetup designed to help developers of all skill levels practice and receive feedback in a supportive and collaborative environment.

Tampa Ruby Brigade - 2006 to Present - Organized the Tampa Ruby Brigade meetup.

Education

University of Arizona

Masters in Management Information Systems

University of Rochester

Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science / Applied Mathematics